<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[aranrees]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[aranrees]]></description>
        <link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 15:56:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="undefinedrss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The End of Unijobbing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The End of Unijobbing</h1><p>What I'm finding interesting right now is the portfolio concept of work. I'm starting to imagine that the idea of having "a job" makes little sense for anyone involved. 

Consider the employer: how does a job end up requiring exactly five days a week to do? Surely that's a major constraint on how flexible a business can be, the need to make jobs fit the standard working week. 

Then we have to ask if seeking the exact mixture of required skills all in one person makes sense. If the job is skilled that is. Surely given full flexibility an employer would prefer two or three people with a wide range of skills to tackle a single job. After all, this is why companies have departments, right? In recognition of the fact that to do the single task of delivering whatever product or service that business delivers requires skills which don't necessarily fit together in one place. 

From a personal perspective what a cruddy situation it is to be looking for one job that satisfies all your needs! How likely is it you'll find a single job that pays what you need and is a perfect match for every skill you wish to use while also covering all the main values you have? 

From a mutual perspective not only does unijobbing put too much pressure on both parties it also limits learning opportunities. If an employer has talent that cross pollinates ideas and attitudes with multiple jobs you're likely to see accelerated learning. And why limit learning to a single beneficiary? If my employee has two jobs and in both jobs he or she is receiving training we both get twice the learning bang for our development buck.

It seems to me that this unijobbing is a vestige of the industrial revolution when we had an explosion of semiskilled jobs that needed to be done repeatedly for months on end with little variation or learning. In such a state you'd look to simplify the logistics by having full time employees (one man one job). Now that assumption, that the logistics of managing multijobbers is a greater burden than the benefit would be worth is looking increasingly dubious. 

We're living in a vestigial, linear unijobbing world that insists on putting people in folders when we'd be far better off attaching multiple tags. A single person should hold multiple jobs and a single job should have multiple people working on it. It just makes more sense. 
</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>undefinedthe-end-of-unijobbing/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7b7c9aff-29f0-4376-a55f-cce24926448f</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 15:56:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>